Marcos Emmanuel Gonzalez Auhing

Quito - Ecuador

■ +593991233962 | ■ marcosgonza.eau@gmail.com | Image https://www.linkedin.com/in/marcosgonzau/

Personal Profile

I am a passionate economist with a solid background in academia, research, and public sector management. At the Ministry of Economy and Finance, I played a key role in the development of green financial tools such as the Sovereign Green Bonds Framework, climate labeling, and initial steps towards green taxonomy. Additionally, I have extensive experience in handling large databases, including information from Ecuador's Social Registry, data from Ecuadorian companies, and the Colombian electric sector. My expertise spans research using DSGE and CGE models, and the use of Machine Learning for macroeconomic forecasts. I possess advanced skills in Python, Spark, and SQL/PostgreSQL, and I have led teams as Technical General Coordinator and National Director of Real Sector Policies.

Education

Universidad EAFIT Medellín, Colombia

MSc. in Economics

- Full Scholarship Cohort 2020
- Teaching and Research Assistant

Escuela Superior Politecnica del Litoral (ESPOL University)

BSc. in Economics

Guayaquil, Ecuador October 2015 - January 2020

February 2020 - August 2021

- Teaching and Research Assistant
- · Student representative on the Disciplinary Commission

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ministry of Economy and Finance

Quito, Ecuador

November 2022 - December 2023

- National Director of Real Sector Policies
- Prepare economic policy proposals for the real sector.
 Coordinate the development of climate finance instruments.
- Develop newsletters and current situation reports for the Real Sector.
- Prepare reports for the monitoring and execution of Social Spending.
- Manage with sectoral ministries the development of public policy matrices.

Unidad del Registro Social

Quito, Ecuador

March 2022 - October 2022

- **General Technical Coordinator**
- Lead and validate the design of methodologies for the creation and updating of indicators.
- Coordinate the development of Social Registry information updating models.
- Lead the design of methodologies for interconnectivity and information exchange.

Advisor to the Executive Board

September 2021 - March 2022

May 2021 - June 2022

- Define strategies oriented to scientific and social research projects.
- Develop socioeconomic projects and plans.
- · Coordinate activities with the technical directorates.

Universidad EAFIT Medellín, Colombia

Advanced Microeconomics I for graduate students in Economics.

- Review, explain and solve exercises proposed by the professor.
- Review of class material.

Teaching assistant

Assistant professor March 2022 - June 2022

- · General Macroeconomics for undergraduate students of the School of Management.
- · Preparation of class material in accordance with planning
- Elaboration and revision of assignments, lessons and exams.

Research assistant February 2020 - June 2021

- Special and weekly reports describing current economic issues in Colombia.
- Degree work: Effects of the productive transformation and energy transition measured through a CGE model.. Advisors: Álvaro Hurtado and Jesús Botero.
- Development and uses of CGE, DSGE, ML models

FEBRUARY 5, 2024

Escuela Superior Politécnica del Litoral (ESPOL University)

Research assistant

Guayaquil, Ecuador May 2019 - January 2020

- · Research assistant to Professor Leonardo Sánchez Aragón, PhD.
- · Analysis of agricultural statistics from the microdata of the ESPAC survey. Spatial Statistics Review.
- · Initial research on the effects of contagion of the fungus Fusarium RT4 in a Network of Banana farmers.
- · Participation in the creation of a database for the construction of a Network on top 5 magazine authors.

Publications

Economic Impacts of Environmental Policies and Electricity Generation. Presented at "26th Annual Conference on Global Economic Analysis (Bordeaux, France)". Purdue University, West Lafayette. Global Trade Analysis Project (GTAP). 2023

Macroeconomía en los tiempos del Covid-19: un análisis de equilibrio dinámico estocástico para Colombia. Chapter 2 of the book "Covid-19 consecuencias y desafíos en la economía colombiana. Una mirada desde las universidades." 2022.

Towards a low-emissions economy: The role of abatement targets and carbon taxes. Presented at "The 24th Annual Conference on Global Economic Analysis (Virtual Conference)". Purdue University, West Lafayette. Global Trade Analysis Project (GTAP). 2021

Continuing Education _____

Diploma in Impact Assessment of Programs and Public Policies

Virtual

Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile - JPAL

September 2022 - December 2022

Summer School of the Economics of Climate Change and Climate Policy

Virtual

Universidad EAFIT June 2021 - July 2021

The Complete Python/PostgreSQL Course 2.0

Virtual

Udemy

March 2021

Data analysis with Python

Virtual

Coursera - IBM

May 2019

Econometrics: Methods and Applications

Virtual

Coursera - Erasmus University Rotterdam

October 2018

Interests and skills

Programming Python, R, SQL, PostgreSQL

Stata, Matlab, ETFX(Overleaf/R Markdown), Tableau, Microsoft Power BI, AWS, Git.

Interests Machine Learning, Network, Evaluation of programs and public policies, Macroeconomía

Language ____

English Intermediate-Advanced

French Spanish

Essential Native

References.

Phd. Leonardo Sánchez Aragón.

Professor and researcher - Escuela Politécnica del Litoral.

Email: lfsanche@espol.edu.ec

Ing. Rossman Camacho

Information System Director - Unidad del Registro Social.

Cell phone: +593 987165940

FEBRUARY 5, 2024